smallpdf.com 2018-05-28

# Smallpdf.com – Legal and Privacy

## Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting our website.

Smallpdf respects your right to privacy in the online world when you use our websites and communicate electronically with us. We take all necessary measures to ensure any personal information you give us is kept secure.

It is fundamentally important that you are informed that the Smallpdf is the Data Controller of your personal information.

We asked ourselves a number of key questions that we believe you would like answered about the personal information that you submit to Smallpdf. These answers will inform you of your rights relating to your personal information and the measures taken to maintain the privacy and security of this personal information. We trust you find this information helpful.

If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices please contact Smallpdf at the address given below.

Key Questions and Answers

1\. What personal information does the Smallpdf collect through its websites and how is it collected?

 **In brief** : _If you use our services, we will collect among other things, your IP address. We do not access your files, copy or back them up. They are always deleted after one hour. If you donate money, purchase third-party software or register a Pro account, we may collect personal information about you._

By visiting any domain or subdomain of smallpdf.com, your IP address and other usage metrics will be logged along with the dates and times of access. If you purchase software via our website, we may collect from you personal data about your names, email address, company name, and license code. If you decide to purchase third party software via our website, we may collect from you personal data about your names, email address, company name, and license code. Please keep in mind that [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/) or [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/) may collect credit card information about you. We neither collect nor have access to such information. Before providing any personal data to [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/), [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/) or [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/), please make sure that you have read their privacy policies.

If you register a Pro account, we may collect your name, address and related information like VAT number, occupation etc. and a. All financial transactions related to the use of Pro accounts are handled through Braintree and PayPal. Any personal information provided by you to Braintree and PayPal will be processed by them in accordance with their privacy policies. We kindly request you to provide your personal information to [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/) and PayPal only after reviewing their privacy policies and understanding what types of personal information they will collect from you. Please note that we DO NOT store your payment information. Braintree and PayPal handle all the steps in the payment process on their websites, including data collection and data processing. The personal information collected in respect to Pro accounts is stored on [Auth0](https://auth0.com/), a company providing single sign-on services. We do not store the information collected in respect to Pro accounts on our own infrastructure.

2\. How does the Smallpdf keep your personal information secure?

 **In brief** : _We do a lot to make our service as secure as possible._

Smallpdf takes all necessary measures to keep your personal information private and secure. Only authorized Smallpdf staff or third-party company staff (i.e. service providers) have access to your personal information. All Smallpdf staff who have access to your personal information are required to adhere to Smallpdf’s Privacy Policy and all third-party employees who have access to your personal information have signed non-disclosure agreements. In addition, contracts are in place with third-party companies that have access to your personal information, to make sure this information remains secure. To ensure your personal information is protected, Smallpdf maintains a secure IT environment and has the appropriate measures in place to prevent unauthorised access (i.e. hacking). All communication and file transfers to and from our server are encrypted with SSL. Passwords for the Pro accounts are never stored in plain text and are encrypted on secure third party services and no one has access to them.

3\. What purposes does Smallpdf use your personal information for?

 **In brief** : _We use your personal data to provide you with high-quality services. Your privacy is our priority. So, we would not use your data for unlawful purposes._

We do log your IP address and other usage metrics for administration and analytical purposes to improve our products

We use the email address collected by you to communicate with you. If you provide us with personal data when purchasing software, we will use that data to issue a software license to you, provide you with a customer support, or issue a refund to you.

All information collected in respect to the registration of your Pro account will be used solely for: (1) providing you with an invoice; (2) allowing you to pay the fees for using your Pro account; (3) managing your Pro account; (4) sending you promotional emails; and (5) delivering our newsletter to you. The VAT number provided by you will be validated by using the VAT-validation service offered by the European Commission.

If you would like to stop receiving promotional emails from us, please send an email to [support@smallpdf.com](mailto:support@smallpdf.com) with the word “Unsubscribe” in the subject line.

4\. Who does Smallpdf disclose your personal information to and why?

 **In brief** : _We share some of your personal data with others in order to provide you with our services. Don’t worry. We would not sell your data or give it to spammers. And we never share or copy your documents uploaded or created on smallpdf.com._

If you would like to purchase software, we will share the personal data collected by us with Solid Documents in order to provide you with the requested software. Solid Documents may use your personal data to send you promotional materials. Before purchasing software, please make sure that you have read the privacy policies of [Solid Documents](http://www.soliddocuments.com/).

Smallpdf will never share your personal information with any Third Party business organisation that intends to use it for direct marketing purposes unless you have given us specific permission to do so.

Smallpdf may share your personal information with Third Parties, but only in the strictly limited circumstances set out below:

  * We may supply your personal information to Third Parties (such as our internet service providers) who help us administer our websites. Some of these business partners may be located outside Switzerland. These Third Parties must at all times provide the same levels of security for your personal information as Smallpdf and are bound by a legal agreement to keep your personal information private and secure and to process it only according to Smallpdf’s specific instructions.

  * We may also supply your personal information to government bodies and law enforcement agencies if: we are required to do so by applicable law; or, if in our good faith judgment, such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal procedures; to respond to any legal claims or actions; or to protect the rights of Smallpdf or its customers and the public.

5\. How can you see, check, change or delete the Personal Information you send to us?

 **In brief** : _If you would like to access, modify, or delete your personal data, just contact us._

We allow you to access, modify, or delete the personal data collected by us. If you would like to do so, please contact us at [info@smallpdf.com](mailto:info@smallpdf.com). We will get back to you as soon as possible.

Please note that uploaded and processed files are never stored longer than an hour on our servers and are then deleted permanently. During this hour, your files are not accessed, copied, analyzed or anything else unless you provide us with the explicit written permission to do so. Please do not contact us for deleting files because they are always deleted automatically within a time period of one hour commencing on the time when you upload them on smallpdf.com.

6\. How do we store User Files and generated Data

 **In brief** : _All files are deleted after one hour. No backups are made and no one has access to your files._

All the files uploaded for processing on smallpdf.com are stored on an appropriate server infrastructure for processing and the download afterwards. All user-uploaded files as well as the converted output files will be deleted one hour after upload or conversion respectively. We keep the files for the sole purpose of giving you enough time to download them. During that hour, we don’t look at the files or mine any data from them. No backups are made of any uploaded files nor their processed output neither are the contents monitored without the explicit permission of user.

7\. Which countries will your personal information be sent to and why?

 **In brief** : _We transfer your personal data outside of Switzerland and ensure that your personal data is well protected irrespective of its location on or outside the planet Earth._

When you use our services, your information, including personal data, may be transferred to and from servers located in the other countries. Uploaded files and generated files through our service are never stored longer than one hour. Also, original user files as well as processed files are never shared with third parties, unless such parties are subject to confidentiality obligations. If you provide personal data to Braintree and PayPal, please bear in mind that [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/), [PayPal](https://www.paypal.com/), [Auth0](https://auth0.com/) and similar provider may transfer your personal data to various countries. eBay Inc., the owner of Braintree and PayPal, has established Binding Corporate Rules explaining how eBay Inc. protects your information. You can find the rules at the following link: [ebayprivacycenter.com](http://ebayprivacycenter.com/).

We comply with the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information Switzerland to the United States.

If we do transfer your personal data outside Switzerland, then we shall make every effort to ensure that your personal data is processed in accordance with the applicable Swiss law.

8\. COOKIES (“Tracking Technology”) – How and why does Smallpdf use them?

A cookie is a small piece of data placed on your computer’s hard drive that enables a service to monitor websites. We do not use any cookies on our site with the exception of cookies solely for functional purposes, without storing any user information. Third party applications that we use, such as Dropbox, Google Drive, Google Analytics, Google DoubleClick, and Google Adsense do use cookies on our site to help analyse the web traffic or determine targeted advertisements based on your preferences. To opt out of Google’s use of cookies, please visit the Google ad and content network privacy policy. If you prefer not to use cookies at all, we recommend adjusting your browser settings accordingly. If you are unsure how to do that, use your favorite search engine to find out everything about it or visit [aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/).

9\. How do we handle Like Buttons?

 **In brief** : _You might not like liking us._

We know that you like to click on “Like” buttons. Therefore, smallpdf.com features “Like” buttons from Google Plus, Facebook and Twitter. However, these “Like” buttons may track users. Before using smallpdf.com, please make sure that you are familiar with the privacy policies of [Google](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation), and [Twitter](https://twitter.com/fr/privacy).

10\. Why do we track Errors?

 **In brief** : _We track errors to improve our product._

Although we put our best efforts to ensure the best quality of our services, sometimes our website may experience tough moments. We use specific services in order to track errors on smallpdf.com that affect our customers. We do not provide such services with personal information about our users.

11\. How long does Smallpdf keep your personal information?

 **In brief** : _We keep your personal data only until it is needed for the provision of our services or required by law._

Please note that uploaded and processed files are never stored longer than an hour on our servers and then are deleted permanently. During this hour your files are not accessed, copied, analyzed or anything else except we have the explicit permission of the user for example for a support case.

We will keep your personal data for as long as it is necessary to provide you with our services. If your personal data is no longer necessary, we can keep it in an identifiable form for maximum one year. However, we are obliged by the Swiss law to keep invoices and transactional data for more than 10 years.

Please bear in mind that, if you cancel a Pro account, we will not delete the personal data provided by you when registering the Pro account.

12\. Can Smallpdf change the terms of this Privacy Policy?

 **In brief** : _If you use our website, you agree with this Privacy Policy. Changes of this Privacy Policy may occur and will be made available to you._

By using our website, you allow us to collect, delete, use, and share your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Smallpdf may occasionally make changes and corrections to this Privacy Notice. Please check this Privacy Policy regularly to see the changes and how these may affect you.

13\. Where can I find more information on legal issues concerning Smallpdf websites and my legal rights and responsibilities?

As Smallpdf is a company based in Switzerland, the laws that govern and apply to this website are those of Switzerland. For more detailed information please consult the “Terms and Conditions” page.

14\. IMPORTANT – Why do I have to accept the terms of this Privacy Notice?

Smallpdf uses the Internet to collect and process your personal information. This naturally involves the processing and transmission of your personal information across borders.

This Privacy Notice provides you with all necessary information (in an easily accessible way) to make an informed choice as to whether to use our websites and to send your personal information to Smallpdf or not.

Therefore, by browsing our websites and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our Processing of your (indirect) personal information (cookies, connection and system information) in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact Smallpdf by using the email [support@smallpdf.com](mailto:support@smallpdf.com) and we will be pleased to assist you with any additional queries you may have.

Zurich, October 2017, Smallpdf GmbH, Zurich

## Smallpdf General Terms and Conditions

Zurich, October, 2017. Replaces the prior versions in their entirety.

These terms govern your use of our website or services such as Smallpdf, Smallpdf PRO, Smallpdf Reader, Smallpdf Desktop (collectively, “ **Services** ”) and software that we include as part of the Services, including any applications, Content Files (defined below), scripts, instruction sets, and any related documentation (collectively “ **Software** ”). By using the Services or Software, you agree to these terms. If you have entered into another agreement with us concerning specific Services or Software, then the terms of that agreement controls where it conflicts with these terms. As discussed further in Section 3 below, you retain all rights and ownership you have in your content that you make available through the Services.

1\. How this Agreement Works

1.1 Choice of Law

Your relationship is with Smallpdf GmbH, a company incorporated under the laws of Switzerland, and the Services and Software are governed by the laws of Switzerland.

1.2 Privacy

The Privacy Policy governs any personal information you provide to us. **By using the Services or Software you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy**.

1.3 Desktop Application Usage Data

Whilst using the Services, you will share information with Smallpdf about how you use our desktop applications. This shared information is associated with your Smallpdf account and allows us to provide you with a more personalized experience, and helps us improve product quality and features. To learn more about desktop application usage data, go to our support page.

1.4 Modification

We may modify, update, or discontinue the Services, Software (including any of their portions or features) at any time without liability to you or anyone else. If we discontinue a Service in its entirety, then we will provide you with a pro rata refund for any unused fees for that Service that you may have prepaid.

2\. Use of Service

2.1 License

Subject to your compliance with these terms and the law, you may access and use the Services.

2.2 Smallpdf Intellectual Property

We (and our licensors) remain the sole owner of all right, title, and interest in the Services and Software. We reserve all rights not granted under these terms. You are especially not allowed to resell any of our products, Software and/or Services.

2.3 Pre-release Version

We may designate the Software or Services, or a feature of the Software or Services, as a pre-release or beta version (“ **Pre-release Version** ”). Pre-release Version does not represent the final product and may contain bugs that may cause system or other failure and data loss. We may choose not to commercially release the Pre-release Version. You must promptly cease using the Pre-release Version and destroy all copies of Pre-release Version if we request you to do so, or if we release a commercial version of the Pre-release Version. Any separate agreement we enter into with you governing the Pre-release Version will supersede the provisions on Pre-Release Version set out in this section.

3\. Your Content

3.1 Ownership

You retain all rights and ownership of your We do not claim any ownership rights to your

3.2 Our Access

We will only access, view, or listen to your content in limited ways. For example, in order to perform the Services, we may need to access, view, or listen to your content to (a) respond to support requests; (b) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, unlawful, or technical issues; and (c) enforce these terms.

4\. Account Information

You are responsible for all activity that occurs via your account. Please notify Customer Support immediately if you become aware of any unauthorized use of your account. You may not (a) Share your account information (except with an authorized account administrator) or (b) use another person’s account. Your account administrator may use your account information to manage your use and access to the Services.

5\. User Conduct

5.1 Responsible Use

You must use the Services responsibly.

5.2 Misuse

You must not misuse the Services, Software, or content that we provide to you as part of the Services or Software. For example, you must not:

(a) copy, modify, host, stream, sublicense, or resell the Services, Software, or content;

(b) enable or allow others to use the Service, Software, or content using your account information;

(c) use the content or Software included in the Services to construct any kind of database;

(d) access or attempt to access the Services by any means other than the interface we provided or authorized;

(e) circumvent any access or use restrictions put into place to prevent certain uses of the Services;

(f) share content or engage in behavior that violates anyone’s Intellectual Property Right (“Intellectual Property Rights” means copyright, moral rights, trademark, trade dress, patent, trade secret, unfair competition, right of privacy, right of publicity, and any other proprietary rights.);

(i) attempt to disable, impair, or destroy the Services, software, or hardware;

(k) engage in chain letters, junk mails, pyramid schemes, spamming, or other unsolicited messages;

(l) place advertisement of any products or services in the Services except with our prior written approval;

(m) use any data mining or similar data gathering and extraction methods in connection with the Services; or

(n) violate applicable law.

6\. Fees and Payment

6.1 Taxes and Third-Party Fees

You must pay any applicable taxes, and any applicable third-party fee (including, for example telephone toll charges, mobile carrier fees, ISP charges, data plan charges, credit card fees, foreign exchange fees, foreign transaction fees). We are not responsible for these fees. Contact your financial institution with questions about fees. We may take steps to collect the fees you owe us. You are responsible for all related collection costs and expenses.

6.2 Credit Card Information

If you do not notify us of updates to your payment method, to avoid interruption of your service, we may participate in programs supported by your card provider to try to update your payment information, and you authorize us to continue billing your account with the updated information that we obtain.

6.3 Billing

We will automatically bill the monthly (1 month) / annually (12 months) membership fee to your Payment Method each selected period until your subscription is cancelled or terminated. If you do not terminate your subscription, it will be automatically renewed.

You and Smallpdf may cancel or terminate your subscription at any time. Any cancellation will take place from the next billing period, i.e. any cancellation will only cancel future billings. **We do not provide refunds** except in cases requested by mandatory law or where otherwise explicitly communicated to user. All fees are exclusive of all taxes, levies, or duties imposed by taxing authorities, and you shall be responsible for payment of all such taxes, levies, or duties.

7\. Your Indemnification Obligations

You will indemnify us and our subsidiaries, affiliates, officers, agents, employees, partners, and licensors from any claim, demand, loss, or damages, including reasonable attorneys’ fees, arising out of or related to your content, your use of the Services or Software, or your violation of these terms.

8\. Disclaimers of Warranties

8.1 The Services and Software are provided “AS-IS”. To the maximum extent permitted by law, we disclaim all warranties express or implied, including the implied warranties of non-infringement, merchantability, and fitness for a particular purpose. We make no commitments about the content within the Services. We further disclaim any warranty that (a) the Services or Software will meet your requirements or will be constantly available, uninterrupted, timely, secure, or error-free; (b) the results that may be obtained from the use of the Services or Software will be effective, accurate, or reliable; (c) the quality of the Services or Software will meet your expectations; or that (d) any errors or defects in the Services or Software will be corrected.

8.2 We specifically disclaim any liability for any actions resulting from your use of any Services or Software. You may use and access the Services or Software at your own discretion and risk, and you are solely responsible for any damage to your computer system or loss of data that results from the use and access of any Service or Software.

9\. Limitation of Liability

9.1 Smallpdf is not liable to you or anyone else for: (a) any loss of use, data, goodwill, or profits, whether or not foreseeable; and (b) any special, incidental, indirect, consequential, or punitive damages whatsoever (even if we have been advised of the possibility of these damages), including those (x) resulting from loss of use, data, or profits, whether or not foreseeable, (y) based on any theory of liability, including breach of contract or warranty, negligence or other tortious action, or (z) arising from any other claim arising out of or in connection with your use of or access to the Services or Software. Nothing in these terms limits or excludes our liability for gross negligence, for our (or our employees’) intentional misconduct, or for death or personal injury.

9.2 Our total liability in any matter arising out of or related to these terms is limited to CHF 100 or the aggregate amount that you paid for access to the Service and Software during the three-month period preceding the event giving rise to the liability, whichever is larger. This limitation will apply even if we have been advised of the possibility of the liability exceeding the amount and notwithstanding any failure of essential purpose of any limited remedy.

9.3 The limitations and exclusions in this Section 9 apply to the maximum extent permitted by law.

10\. Termination

10.1 Termination by You

You may stop using the Services at any time. Termination of your account does not relieve you of any obligation to pay any outstanding fees.

10.2 Termination by Us

Smallpdf may terminate the Service/this agreement at any time. If we terminate these terms for reasons other than for cause, then we will make reasonable effort to notify you at least 30 days prior to termination via the email address you provide to us with instructions on how to retrieve your We may, at any time, terminate your right to use and access the Services or Software if:

(a) you breach any provision of these terms (or act in a manner that clearly shows you do not intend to, or are unable to, comply with these terms);

(b) you fail to make the timely payment of fees for the Software or the Services, if any;

(c) we are required to do so by law (for example, where the provision of the Services or Software to you is, or becomes, unlawful);

(d) we elect to discontinue the Services or Software, in whole or in part, (such as if it becomes impractical for us to continue offering Services in your region due to change of law); or

(e) there has been an extended period of inactivity in your free account.

10.3 Survival

Upon expiration or termination of these terms, any perpetual licenses you have granted, your indemnification obligations, our warranty disclaimers or limitations of liabilities, and dispute resolution provisions stated in these terms will survive. Upon the expiration or termination of the Services, some or all of the Software may cease to operate without prior notice.

11\. Investigations / Disclosure

We may access or disclose information about you, or your use of the Services, (a) when it is required by law; (b) to respond to your requests for customer service support; or (c) when we, in our discretion, think it is necessary to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of us, our users, or the public.

12\. Dispute Resolution

12.1 Process

For any concern or dispute you may have, you agree to first try to resolve the dispute informally by contacting us. If a dispute is not resolved within 30 days of submission, you or Smallpdf must resolve any claims relating to these terms, the Services, or the Software through final and binding arbitration, except that you or Smallpdf may assert claims before the courts of the Canton of Zurich, Switzerland.

12.2 Rules

If you or Smallpdf decide to resort to arbitration as per the foregoing paragraph, the Swiss Chambers’ Arbitration Institution will administer the arbitration in Zurich under the Swiss Rules of International Arbitration. There will be one arbitrator that you and Smallpdf both select. The arbitration will be conducted in the English language. Judgment upon the award rendered may be entered and will be enforceable in any court of competent jurisdiction having jurisdiction over the parties.

12.3 No Class Actions

You may only resolve disputes with us on an individual basis, and may not bring a claim as a plaintiff or a class member in a class, consolidated, or representative action.

12.4 Injunctive Relief

Notwithstanding the foregoing, in the event of your or others’ unauthorized access to or use of the Services or content in violation of these terms you agree that we are entitled to apply for injunctive remedies (or an equivalent type of urgent legal relief) in any jurisdiction.

13\. Compliance with Licenses

If you are a business, company, or organization, then we may, no more than once every 12 months, upon seven 7 days’ prior notice to you, appoint our personnel or an independent third party auditor who is obliged to maintain confidentiality to inspect (including manual inspection, electronic methods, or both) your records, systems, and facilities to verify that your installation and use of any and all Software or Services is in conformity with its valid licenses from us. Additionally, you will provide us with all records and information requested by us in order to verify that its installation and use of any and all Software and Services is in conformity with your valid licenses from us within 30 days of our request. If the verification discloses a shortfall in licenses for the Software or Services, you will immediately acquire any necessary licenses, subscriptions, and any applicable back maintenance and support. If the underpaid fees exceed 5% of the value of the payable license fees, then you will also pay for our reasonable cost of conducting the verification.

14\. Modification

We may modify these terms or any additional terms that apply to a Service or Software to, for example, reflect changes to the law or changes to our Services or Software. You should look at the terms regularly. We will post notice of modifications to these terms on this page. We will post notice of modified additional terms in the applicable Service or Software. By continuing to use or access the Services or Software after the revisions come into effect, you agree to be bound by the revised terms.

15\. Miscellaneous

15.1 English Version

The English version of these terms will be the version used when interpreting or construing these terms.

15.2 Notice to Smallpdf

You may send the notices to us at the following address: Smallpdf GmbH, Staffelstrasse 10, 8045 Zurich, Switzerland.

15.3 Notice to You

We may notify you by email, postal mail, postings within the Services, or other legally acceptable means.

15.4 Entire Agreement

These terms constitute the entire agreement between you and us regarding your use of the Services and Software and supersede any prior agreements between you and us relating to the Services.

15.5 Non-Assignment

You may not assign or otherwise transfer these terms or your rights and obligations under these terms, in whole or in part, without our written consent and any such attempt will be void. We may transfer our rights under these terms to a third party.

15.6 Severability

If a particular term is not enforceable, the unenforceability of that term will not affect any other terms.

15.7 No Waiver

Our failure to enforce or exercise any of these terms is not a waiver of that section.

## Imprint

 **In brief** : _Legal information about our company required by German law_.

Smallpdf LLC is responsible for Smallpdf.

Name and address of the company

Smallpdf LLC

Staffelstrasse 10

8045 Zurich

Switzerland

Directors

Manuel Stofer

Christoph Forsting

Ihr Kontakt zu Smallpdf GmbH

Smallpdf GmbH

Staffelstrasse 10

8045 Zurich

Switzerland

Registry Info

Handelsregister des Kantons Zürichs (Chamber of Commerce in Zurich)

Registry Number: CHE-461.243.982

VAT Registry Number (Umsatzsteuer-Identifikationsnummer)

CHE-461.243.982 MWST

European Union VAT Registry Number

EU276001661
